<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scene on Santosh</title>
    <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/tags/scene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scene on Santosh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/tags/scene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customer churn prediction</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement A Bank wants to take care of customer retention for its product: savings accounts. The bank wants you to identify customers likely to churn balances below the minimum balance. I have the customers information such as age, gender, demographics along with their transactions with the bank. My task as a data scientist would be to predict the propensity to churn for each customer. Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plant Seedling Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-0/</guid>
      <description>Problem statement To identify species of a given image (which class it belongs to, out of 12 weed species). To develop a CNN model, trained on “V-2 plant seedlings dataset”. Dataset “V-2 plant seedlings dataset” having 5539 images of crop and weeds. Weeds belongs to 12 different category. Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Data Science Salary Estimator</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Created a tool that estimates data science salaries (MAE ~ $ 11K) to help data scientists negotiate their income when they get a job. Scraped over 1000 job descriptions from glassdoor using python and selenium. Engineered features from the text of each job description to quantify the value companies put on python, excel, aws, and spark. Optimized Linear, Lasso, and Random Forest Regressors using GridsearchCV to reach the best model.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
