<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Santosh</title>
    <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Santosh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 11:13:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Face Swap Flask Web App</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next word prediction using LSTM</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Aim To train and develop an LSTM model on text data to predict the next words in a sentence. Data Required text data has been taken from book ‘The republic’ by Plato. Summary Steps involved in this project Preprocessing Tokenization Vectorization Model Building &amp;amp; Training Production deployment Django&#xA;AWS cloud deployment&#xA;![targets](&amp;quot;/images/next_word_interface.png&amp;quot;) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customer churn prediction</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement A Bank wants to take care of customer retention for its product: savings accounts. The bank wants you to identify customers likely to churn balances below the minimum balance. I have the customers information such as age, gender, demographics along with their transactions with the bank. My task as a data scientist would be to predict the propensity to churn for each customer. Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter VI: Esmeralda</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to be able to inform the reader, that during the whole of this scene, Gringoire and his piece had stood firm. His actors, spurred on by him, had not ceased to spout his comedy, and he had not ceased to listen to it. He had made up his mind about the tumult, and was determined to proceed to the end, not giving up the hope of a return of attention on the part of the public.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter V: Quasimodo</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>In the twinkling of an eye, all was ready to execute Coppenole’s idea. Bourgeois, scholars and law clerks all set to work. The little chapel situated opposite the marble table was selected for the scene of the grinning match. A pane broken in the pretty rose window above the door, left free a circle of stone through which it was agreed that the competitors should thrust their heads. In order to reach it, it was only necessary to mount upon a couple of hogsheads, which had been produced from I know not where, and perched one upon the other, after a fashion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plant Seedling Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-0/</guid>
      <description> Problem statement To identify species of a given image (which class it belongs to, out of 12 weed species). To develop a CNN model, trained on “V-2 plant seedlings dataset”. Dataset “V-2 plant seedlings dataset” having 5539 images of crop and weeds. Weeds belongs to 12 different category. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Data Science Salary Estimator</title>
      <link>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://santosh175.github.io/me_portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Created a tool that estimates data science salaries (MAE ~ $ 11K) to help data scientists negotiate their income when they get a job. Scraped over 1000 job descriptions from glassdoor using python and selenium. Engineered features from the text of each job description to quantify the value companies put on python, excel, aws, and spark. Optimized Linear, Lasso, and Random Forest Regressors using GridsearchCV to reach the best model.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
